<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wenqian Hugo Homepage</title>
    <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Wenqian Hugo Homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://Wenqian1228.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/readings/kongzi_zwq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/readings/kongzi_zwq/</guid>
      <description>整理了下「孔子世家」的读书笔记:
说实话看完孔子世家，我越发觉得对司马迁肃然起敬，在那个汉武帝的时代能对孔子写出这样的评价，值得被历史铭记。
首先我觉得孔子明显是一个长袖善舞的人，周游列国只求做官，妄想挥斥方裘。嘴上说着“君君，臣臣，父父，子子”，但是从来都没有忠于一位诸侯，也没有臣为君死，鞠躬尽瘁的魄力。也难怪他在齐景公那里被晏婴打成右派，说他“倨傲自顺”。总能以极高的道德标准和极其严苛的理法去要求别人，但是到自己每当做出不齿的行为，却总能给自己找到理由。鲁公问政孔子，孔子的第一反应是 要正名分！比什么都重要！编出一堆歪理来回答子路的质问。千人千面，和不同人永远是不同态度，并且大肆歌颂自己这种。一边大肆宣扬道德标准，但是自己出门就违背和蒲人的契约，又一点原则也没有，一个借口就违约了。
史记里吹嘘的孔子博学，某种程度上就像是流浪的吉普赛人，只知道一些奇闻异事：比如巨人骨架的出处，比如隼身上的箭头出处。但是同时他也把人分成三六九等，完全瞧不起女性：“彼妇之口，可以出走，彼妇之谒，可以死败，盖优哉游哉，维以卒岁。”
我觉得他这个人真的是分虚伪，在匡国被困时，热血沸腾的呵斥：“天之未丧斯文也，匡人其如予何！”一顿豪言壮语后，留了一个自己的随从给人家当家臣，然后才脱身，实在是讽刺啊，所以当代世界这些狗屁政客干的苟且之事，粉饰太平，高声呼号，都是从孔子那里学来的儒家文化。身为人师，鲁康子找冉求辅政，孔子却心生嫉妒不悦。叶公问子路孔子，子路不答，孔子也生气，质问子路为何不炫耀自己：“由，尔何不对曰‘其为人也，学道不倦，诲人不厌，发愤忘食，乐以忘忧，不知老之将至’”自己夸自己。实在是小气啊。
再从孔子对弟子的态度来看更可见其人品。孔子带着学生被控在蔡国，陈国之间，徒弟们饥困交加，都不满意。他把子路 子贡 颜回三人叫来。子路说：“我们仁德和智谋不够，所以人家不相信我们”？子贡更是热脸贴冷屁股：“老师的道理大到极点，使人不能容忍，为何不降低迁就一下？”都被孔子喷了。到了颜回：”天下人不容人，正见的老师是君子。一个人道术不修治才是耻辱，一个人道术修正不被重用，那是国家的执政者的耻辱。正见得老师是君子啊！“ 所以最会反思，最会自省的都被批评了，而最阿谀奉承的最受喜欢。圣人孔子抵不住三个马屁，讽刺啊。最后却还是把子贡送到楚国才得以逃困，所以啊，人善被人欺是从孔子出来的。
最后的最后，还要和项羽一样自怨自艾，怪老天不够赏识自己，是自己的才能没能发挥作用。大哥您不当官确实浪费了，你不在21世纪当官更加浪费了。
我觉得，孔子在当代，如果从政一定会混的很好，擅长斗争和诡辩，还很擅长推卸责任。如果在企业上班一定是一个ppt好手，疯狂跳槽，忽悠骗钱的职业高管。
最后我觉得司马迁引用《诗》的那句“高山仰止，景行行止，虽不能至，然心向往之”是最大的讽刺，是明褒实贬，实在是高。</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘Democracy’ by and for the Elites</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/readings/democracy_wsj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/readings/democracy_wsj/</guid>
      <description>Go back
President Biden’s Sept. 1 speech in Philadelphia on “unity” is a poignant example of the confusion surrounding the concept of democracy. Mr. Biden declared that MAGA Republicans threaten “the very foundations of our republic.” The phrase a “threat to American democracy” is so commonplace these days that it hardly carries any meaning—except that it encapsulates the reigning ideology of our time, an ideology so pervasive that it almost goes unnoticed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am currently a Ph.D. student at the Department of Computer Science and Engineering, The Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK), under the supervision of Prof. Bei Yu since Fall 2020. Previously, I received my B.S. in the Department of Computer Science and Engineering from The Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK) in 2019.
My current works and research interests are mainly around:
Efficient AI: Hardware-aware model compression &amp;amp; quantization</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/experience/</guid>
      <description>Education: Ph.D. Computer Science and Engineering, Aug 2020 - present
The Chinese University of Hong Kong
B.S. Computer Science and Engineering(Exchange), Aug 2017 - Jan 2018
Nanyang Technological University
Summer School, Jun 2017 - Jul 2017
Oxford University
B.S. Computer Science and Engineering, Sept 2015 - Nov 2019
The Chinese University of Hong Kong
Occupational history: Research Intern | SmartMore
Heterogeneous Computing Cetre
Jun. 2020 - Jan. 2021, Shenzhen, China</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Others</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/others/</guid>
      <description>I have broad interests in many things irrelavant to my research.
Used to love photography but not that much recently. A brief selection on Instagram(@vincent_zhao1228).
I enjoy reading and occasionally intrigued by interesting opinions or ideas. A small collection of books/articles
I love coffee and some acoustic music in the morning.
Never tired of exploring food cultures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Conference: [C12] Jiaxi Jiang, Lancheng Zou, Wenqian Zhao, Zhuolun He, Tinghuan Chen, Bei Yu, “PDRC: Package Design Rule Checking via GPU-Accelerated Geometric Intersection Algorithms for Non-Manhattan Geometry”, ACM/IEEE Design Automation Conference (DAC), San Francisco, Jun. 23–27, 2024.
[C11] Zixiao Wang, Yunheng Shen, Xufeng Yao, Wenqian Zhao, Yang Bai, Farzan Farnia, Bei Yu, “ChatPattern: Layout Pattern Customization via Natural Language”, ACM/IEEE Design Automation Conference (DAC), San Francisco, Jun. 23–27, 2024.
[C10] Xufeng Yao, Fanbin Lu, Yuechen Zhang, Xinyun Zhang, Wenqian Zhao, Bei Yu, &amp;ldquo;Progressively Knowledge Distillation via Re-parameterizing Diffusion Reverse Process&amp;rdquo;, AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, (AAAI), Feb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading List</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/reading_list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/reading_list/</guid>
      <description>Books On Earth We&amp;rsquo;re Briefly Gorgeous
by Ocean Vuong
Beautiful language and the most detailed narration take you to the cruel yet warmest journey of this young Vietnamese American boy. The war, the rusted youth, the homosexuality, the shattered family, the memory flashbacks mixed with imaginations, written in the letter from the son to his Already-Vietnamese mother.
「史记-高祖本纪 &amp;amp; 项羽本纪」
by 司马迁
项羽不足为谋，骁勇善战，刚愎自用，范增事此主，实属悲哀。舜之后重瞳子又如何，垓下一战，实早晚定局。非天之亡羽，人事不尽，落得江前自刎。而刘邦小人做尽，终成大业。鉴古观今，仍难掩唏嘘。
L&amp;rsquo;Étranger
by Albert Camus
Saddened yet peaceful while reading this short story, same as the summer night before Meursault was sent to Guillotine.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Idiots Can Kill You !</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/readings/idiots_joke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/readings/idiots_joke/</guid>
      <description>Idiots in the office are just as hazardous to your health as cigarettes, caffeine or greasy food, an eye-opening new study reveals. In fact, those dopes can kill you!
Stress is one of the top causes of heart attacks &amp;ndash; and working with stupid people on a daily basis is one of the deadliest forms of stress, according to researchers at Sweden&amp;rsquo;s Lindbergh University Medical Center.
The author of the study, Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
