<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wenqian Hugo Homepage</title>
    <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Wenqian Hugo Homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://Wenqian1228.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>‘Democracy’ by and for the Elites</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/readings/democracy_wsj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/readings/democracy_wsj/</guid>
      <description>Go back
President Biden’s Sept. 1 speech in Philadelphia on “unity” is a poignant example of the confusion surrounding the concept of democracy. Mr. Biden declared that MAGA Republicans threaten “the very foundations of our republic.” The phrase a “threat to American democracy” is so commonplace these days that it hardly carries any meaning—except that it encapsulates the reigning ideology of our time, an ideology so pervasive that it almost goes unnoticed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am currently a Ph.D. student at the Department of Computer Science and Engineering, The Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK), under the supervision of Prof. Bei Yu since Fall 2020. Previously, I received my B.S. in the Department of Computer Science and Engineering from The Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK) in 2019.
My current works and research interests are mainly around:
Efficient AI: Hardware-aware model compression &amp;amp; quantization</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/experience/</guid>
      <description>Education: Ph.D. Computer Science and Engineering, Aug 2020 - present
The Chinese University of Hong Kong
B.S. Computer Science and Engineering(Exchange), Aug 2017 - Jan 2018
Nanyang Technological University
Summer School, Jun 2017 - Jul 2017
Oxford University
B.S. Computer Science and Engineering, Sept 2015 - Nov 2019
The Chinese University of Hong Kong
Occupational history: Research Intern | SmartMore
Heterogeneous Computing Cetre
Jun. 2020 - Jan. 2021, Shenzhen, China</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Others</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/others/</guid>
      <description>I have broad interests in many things irrelavant to my research.
Used to love photography but not that much recently. A brief selection on Instagram(@vincent_zhao1228).
I enjoy reading and occasionally intrigued by interesting opinions or ideas. A small collection of books/articles
Recently I am starting to dig into modern Chinese history in my spare time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Conference: [C5] Zehua Pei, Wenqian Zhao, Zhuolun He, Bei Yu, “Bit-Level Quantization for Efficient Layout Hotspot Detection”, International Symposium of EDA (ISEDA) (ISEDA), May 9–11, 2023.
[C4] Zixiao Wang, Yunheng Shen, Wenqian Zhao, Yang Bai, Guojin Chen, Farzan Farnia, Bei Yu, “DiffPattern: Layout Pattern Generation via Discrete Diffusion”, ACM/IEEE Design Automation Conference (DAC) (DAC), Jul. 9 – 13, 2023.
[C3] Wenqian Zhao, Xufeng Yao, Ziyang Yu, Guojin Chen, Yuzhe Ma, Bei Yu, Martin D.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading List</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/reading_list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/reading_list/</guid>
      <description>Books The Making of the Modern Chinese State: 1600–1950
by Huaiyin Li
Very informative, with many detailed discussion and analyses, and yet still in a compact structure.
Education
by Tara Westover
Always reminds me the essence of getting eduacated which is probably the only chance to get to know the world and the only thing I never regret in my life for once.
Ariticles ‘Democracy’ by and for the Elites</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
