<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wenqian Hugo Homepage</title>
    <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Wenqian Hugo Homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://Wenqian1228.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>‘Democracy’ by and for the Elites</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/readings/democracy_wsj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/readings/democracy_wsj/</guid>
      <description>Go back
President Biden’s Sept. 1 speech in Philadelphia on “unity” is a poignant example of the confusion surrounding the concept of democracy. Mr. Biden declared that MAGA Republicans threaten “the very foundations of our republic.” The phrase a “threat to American democracy” is so commonplace these days that it hardly carries any meaning—except that it encapsulates the reigning ideology of our time, an ideology so pervasive that it almost goes unnoticed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am currently a Ph.D. student at the Department of Computer Science and Engineering, The Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK), under the supervision of Prof. Bei Yu since Fall 2020. Previously, I received my B.S. in the Department of Computer Science and Engineering from The Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK) in 2019.
My current works and research interests are mainly around:
Efficient AI: Hardware-aware model compression &amp;amp; quantization</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/experience/</guid>
      <description>Education: Ph.D. Computer Science and Engineering, Aug 2020 - present
The Chinese University of Hong Kong
B.S. Computer Science and Engineering(Exchange), Aug 2017 - Jan 2018
Nanyang Technological University
Summer School, Jun 2017 - Jul 2017
Oxford University
B.S. Computer Science and Engineering, Sept 2015 - Nov 2019
The Chinese University of Hong Kong
Occupational history: Research Intern | SmartMore
Heterogeneous Computing Cetre
Jun. 2020 - Jan. 2021, Shenzhen, China</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Others</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/others/</guid>
      <description>I have broad interests in many things irrelavant to my research.
Used to love photography but not that much recently. A brief selection on Instagram(@vincent_zhao1228).
I enjoy reading and occasionally intrigued by interesting opinions or ideas. A small collection of books/articles
I love coffee and some acoustic music in the morning.
Never tired of exploring food cultures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Conference: [C12] Jiaxi Jiang, Lancheng Zou, Wenqian Zhao, Zhuolun He, Tinghuan Chen, Bei Yu, “PDRC: Package Design Rule Checking via GPU-Accelerated Geometric Intersection Algorithms for Non-Manhattan Geometry”, ACM/IEEE Design Automation Conference (DAC), San Francisco, Jun. 23–27, 2024.
[C11] Zixiao Wang, Yunheng Shen, Xufeng Yao, Wenqian Zhao, Yang Bai, Farzan Farnia, Bei Yu, “ChatPattern: Layout Pattern Customization via Natural Language”, ACM/IEEE Design Automation Conference (DAC), San Francisco, Jun. 23–27, 2024.
[C10] Xufeng Yao, Fanbin Lu, Yuechen Zhang, Xinyun Zhang, Wenqian Zhao, Bei Yu, &amp;ldquo;Progressively Knowledge Distillation via Re-parameterizing Diffusion Reverse Process&amp;rdquo;, AAAI Conference on Artificial Intelligence, (AAAI), Feb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading List</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/reading_list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/reading_list/</guid>
      <description>Books 「史记-高祖本纪 &amp;amp; 项羽本纪」
by 司马迁
项羽不足为谋，骁勇善战，刚愎自用，范增事此主，实属悲哀。舜之后重瞳子又如何，垓下一战，实早晚定局。非天之亡羽，人事不尽，落得江前自刎。而刘邦小人做尽，终成大业。鉴古观今，仍难掩唏嘘。
L&amp;rsquo;Étranger
by Albert Camus
Saddened yet peaceful while reading this short story, same as the summer night before Meursault was sent to Guillotine. Being an outsider is even tougher at this time, I guess.
Cien años de soledad (百年孤独)
by Gabriel García Márquez Read this legendary masterwork at the age of 26. Living for three or four times through the whole century is what I feel when each chapter went through my mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Idiots Can Kill You !</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/readings/idiots_joke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/readings/idiots_joke/</guid>
      <description>Idiots in the office are just as hazardous to your health as cigarettes, caffeine or greasy food, an eye-opening new study reveals. In fact, those dopes can kill you!
Stress is one of the top causes of heart attacks &amp;ndash; and working with stupid people on a daily basis is one of the deadliest forms of stress, according to researchers at Sweden&amp;rsquo;s Lindbergh University Medical Center.
The author of the study, Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
