<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wenqian Hugo Homepage</title>
    <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Wenqian Hugo Homepage</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://Wenqian1228.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>‘Democracy’ by and for the Elites</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/readings/democracy_wsj/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/readings/democracy_wsj/</guid>
      <description>Go back
President Biden’s Sept. 1 speech in Philadelphia on “unity” is a poignant example of the confusion surrounding the concept of democracy. Mr. Biden declared that MAGA Republicans threaten “the very foundations of our republic.” The phrase a “threat to American democracy” is so commonplace these days that it hardly carries any meaning—except that it encapsulates the reigning ideology of our time, an ideology so pervasive that it almost goes unnoticed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>I am currently a Ph.D. student at the Department of Computer Science and Engineering, The Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK), under the supervision of Prof. Bei Yu since Fall 2020. Previously, I received my B.S. in the Department of Computer Science and Engineering from The Chinese University of Hong Kong (CUHK) in 2019.
My current works and research interests are mainly around:
Efficient AI: Hardware-aware model compression &amp;amp; quantization</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/experience/</guid>
      <description>Education: Ph.D. Computer Science and Engineering, Aug 2020 - present
The Chinese University of Hong Kong
B.S. Computer Science and Engineering(Exchange), Aug 2017 - Jan 2018
Nanyang Technological University
Summer School, Jun 2017 - Jul 2017
Oxford University
B.S. Computer Science and Engineering, Sept 2015 - Nov 2019
The Chinese University of Hong Kong
Occupational history: Research Intern | SmartMore
Heterogeneous Computing Cetre
Jun. 2020 - Jan. 2021, Shenzhen, China</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Others</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/others/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/others/</guid>
      <description>I have broad interests in many things irrelavant to my research.
Used to love photography but not that much recently. A brief selection on Instagram(@vincent_zhao1228).
I enjoy reading and occasionally intrigued by interesting opinions or ideas. A small collection of books/articles
I love coffee and some acoustic music in the morning.
Never tired of exploring food cultures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Publications</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/publications/</guid>
      <description>Conference: [C9] Shuo Yin*, Wenqian Zhao*, Li Xie, Hong Chen, Yuzhe Ma, Tsung-Yi Ho, Bei Yu, &amp;ldquo;FuILT: Full Chip ILT System With Boundary Healing&amp;rdquo;, International Symposium on Physical Design, (ISPD), Mar. 12-15, 2024.
[C8] Yang Bai*, Wenqian Zhao*, Shuo Yin, Zixiao Wang, Bei Yu, &amp;ldquo;ATFormer: A Learned Performance Model with Transfer Learning Across Devices for Large-Scale Transformers&amp;rdquo;, Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing (EMNLP), Dec. 6-10, 2023.
[C7] Wenqian Zhao*, Shuo Yin*, Chen Bai, Zixiao Wang, Bei Yu, &amp;ldquo;BAQE: A Backend-Adaptive DNN Quantization Flow&amp;rdquo;, International Conference on Computer Vision (ICCV) - LBQNN Workshop (Oral), Oct.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reading List</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/reading_list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/reading_list/</guid>
      <description>Books Cien años de soledad (百年孤独)
by Gabriel García Márquez Read this legendary masterwork at the age of 26. Living for three or four times through the whole century is what I feel when each chapter went through my mind. At the end of the time, nothing escapes fate and reincarnation.
The Making of the Modern Chinese State: 1600–1950
by Huaiyin Li
Very informative, with many detailed discussion and analyses, and yet still in a compact structure.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Working with Idiots Can Kill You !</title>
      <link>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/readings/idiots_joke/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Wenqian1228.github.io/readings/idiots_joke/</guid>
      <description>Idiots in the office are just as hazardous to your health as cigarettes, caffeine or greasy food, an eye-opening new study reveals. In fact, those dopes can kill you!
Stress is one of the top causes of heart attacks &amp;ndash; and working with stupid people on a daily basis is one of the deadliest forms of stress, according to researchers at Sweden&amp;rsquo;s Lindbergh University Medical Center.
The author of the study, Dr.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
